[ ♪ ♪ ]
Today is a good day to die .
[ SCREAMING ]
What 's happening ? It 's crack . Get some help .
So many crackheads , we don 't have time for anybody else .
What have we got ? Some kind of hemorrhage .
Husband brought her in a taxi . Blood pressure ?
90 over 60 and dropping ...
Vaginal bleeding ? What 's he saying ?
Jeez , it 's probably a street abortion .
Probably the uterine artery .
Come on ! We 've got to open her up .
NURSE : All the OR 's are full . It 'll be another 10 minutes .
Yeah , well , that 's too late . Ger her under .
NURSE : Who 's gonna do the surgery ?
I am . NURSE : You can 't !
Just do it !
[ MAN SPEAKING IN SPANISH ]
Get him out of here . Get him out of here !
NURSE : Fifteen years on the job and you 're gonna get me canned in one day . You 're crazy .
All right , here we go . Shh ! Shh ! Shh !
[ WOMAN GRUNTING ]
All right , forceps !
Where the hell is it ? Where is it ? Where is it ? Clamp ! Clamp !
ORDERLY : Get it , Dave . Get it .
You got her . All right , I 've got her .
Dave , get out of here . Now ! NURSE : I tried to stop him .
Labraccio ! What the hell do you think you 're doing ?
[ ♪ ♪ ]
STECKLE : Randall STECKLE , " Diary of a Surgeon . " Not a surgeon yet .
Randall STECKLE , " Diary of a Surgeon-to-be . "
No , wimpy .
Randall STECKLE , " Making of a ... " Pbbt !
Randall STECKLE , " Forging of a Surgeon . " No , pretentious .
Randall STECKLE , " Genesis " ?
Randall STECKLE , " Genesis of a Young Surgeon . " Brilliant !
[ MEN SPEAKING INDISTINCTLY ]
Morning .
Nice work . Keep it up .
WOMAN : Suddenly , even though I was in a coma , I saw myself .
Like , from above , looking down .
Ralph , my husband , was crying .
And the doctor was saying I was dying .
And I saw myself in the bed and everything .
And I started to float out into the hall .
And then into this tunnel toward this light .
And it was the most beautiful light I ever saw .
And I heard this voice .
And it was the most beautiful voice I ever heard .
And it said ,
" I 'm going to take your baby . "
" But you are going back . "
And I woke up ,
and there was Ralph and the doctor .
I was legally dead for four and a half minutes .
But I didn 't see no tunnel and I didn 't see no light .
Oh , I did and it was so beautiful ! Shh .
I was in this garden ... TERRY : This tunnel and this light ,
and then this ... Like , a guide , and a chariot and music .
Terry , I think they 'd better get you off medication .
[ MAN WHISTLES ]
Thanks .
What 's up ? Good morning .
There 's trouble in ER . Better watch your ass today .
Thanks .
Why are you always asking the patients about death anyway ?
I 'm gonna be late for class . Thanks , Edna .
STECKLE : The spoils of arthritis . Some rather resilient inflammatory tissue here .
Trying to sever ... Come on , damn it .
We 're now beneath the transverse arch of the foot .
The three cuneiforms , the five metatarsals .
Brilliant , Dr. STECKLE . You be sure to bring all that talent with you tonight , okay ?
Nelson , about tonight . It 's because I like you as much as I do that I have to decline on moral grounds .
Look , isn 't there enough atrocity in the world without your own little horror ?
Horror ? STECKLE , it 's ignorance we fear .
Since when did truth and knowledge become a horror ?
Especially to a scientist and a genius like yourself .
[ STECKLE CHUCKLES ]
Good morning , Mannus ? How you doing ?
Fine .
I 've been meaning to ask you something , are you dating anyone ?
Identify . Costodiaphragmatic recess .
Look , it 's not offensive if I make conversation , is it ?
I mean , sometimes it 's nice to open up , that 's all . Like old Lenny here , he 's open .
Identify . Pylorus .
Look ,
I 've heard all the rumors and nicknames about you , Rachel .
But I 'm sure you 're a very warm woman . Not the least bit frigid or repressed .
Identify . Your brains .
JOE : Good . RACHEL : Mm-hm .
JOE : So you wanna come over to my place ? Where we can do some more serious thinking .
Excuse me , Dr. Hurley , I need a word with Dr. Mannus .
Sure .
Didn 't I already say no to this ?
Look , I 've already got STECKLE and Hurley .
Two of the top GPA 's in the school .
All I need you to do is handle the injections and the IV .
Forget it , Nelson , I have no interest in watching you kill yourself .
I think you do .
Good morning , class . Today 's exam will be scaled .
Three A 's will be given , five B 's , 10 C 's ,
and the remaining four will get D 's and F 's .
[ ALL GROANING ]
Once again , as in life , you are not in competition with me , yourself or this exam ,
but with each other . Piece of cake .
Look , there are a lot of others in this school who 'd like to make a name for themselves off of something like this .
Just seems a shame to me the people with the ability don 't have the nerve .
[ BOTH SCOFF ]
All right , you want us there , then we 'll be there , Nelson .
Hey , speak for yourself , Joseph .
Sure , it 'll be dramatic , Nelson . You 'll cry , faint , puke at best .
But then what ? Because frankly I don 't think you have the balls .
You just bring the equipment . I 'll bring my balls .
Did you hear about Labraccio ?
Dave , it 's a four-month suspension . It 's not even gonna affect your scholarship .
Forget it , I 'm out of here .
You 're the best student this school 's ever had . They don 't let a guy like you walk away from medicine .
Besides , you were wrong . No , goddamn it ! She was dying .
I saved her life . All right , now what the hell would you have done ?
Why are you taking this personally ?
Of course they 're gonna make an example out of you .
They have to protect their insurance bond .
They 'll ask you back next term .
It doesn 't matter . Because given the same situation , I would do it again .
I know you would .
That 's exactly why I need you there tonight .
There are a few people that I would like to kill right now .
You , however , are not one of them .
Hey . I don 't wanna die .
I want to come back with the answers to death and life .
I can get there with the others ,
but I need you . I need you to bring me back . Please .
I 'm sorry , man , I can 't do that .
Great .
Why don 't you just walk away , Dave ? Go climb a mountain .
You know , I don 't even understand you anymore .
You burned your career today on a stranger .
Now you 're turning your back on a friend .
Look , I 'm real sorry about what happened today , okay ? I really am .
But what are my chances of making it back without you ?
So don 't do it .
[ ♪ ♪ ]
Hey , Dave .
What if it works ?
Hi .
[ MUSIC PLAYING OVER HEADPHONES ]
I don 't want to be buried on Saturday .
It costs $ 150 more to be buried on Saturday .
Mrs. Amsler , you 're doing much better .
[ BELL TOLLING ]
[ JOE PANTING ]
[ WOMAN MOANING ]
[ BED CREAKING ]
[ PHONE RINGING ]
JOE [ OVER SPEAKER ] : Leave a message after the beep .
[ BEEPS ]
NELSON [ OVER SPEAKER ] : Dr. Hurley , I know you 're home .
Don 't be late . Don 't forget the camera .
What camera ?
[ ♪ ♪ ]
[ CLATTERING ]
Shit .
Ah , the bed . Thank God he called a specialist .
No lectures , okay , STECKLE ?
Why should I expect that after you become engaged , you might grow up ?
Did it ever dawn on you that I 'm trying to work some things out ?
Recording a few last adventures before I resign to a life of monogamy .
No , never dawned on me for a moment .
But the words " pussy marauder " do pop into mind occasionally .
What the hell are we doing here ? This is goodbye , med school . Goodbye , career .
Chill out , Randall . Ten bucks says he doesn 't do it .
He shits his drawers and we 're out of here .
NELSON : Not those lights . Security will come running .
Set up over the grate . I just got the boiler going .
You 're really gonna do this ? Just humor the man .
You 're gonna take me down with nitrous , sodium pentothal and a refrigerated blanket .
I 've got some chilled D5W in the cooler .
When my body temperature hits 86 degrees , you 're gonna hit me with 200 joules .
The electric current will stop my heart . When the heart is dead , take the mask off .
Where 's Mannus ? I thought you said Rachel was coming .
STECKLE , shut the door . STECKLE : Wait a minute .
I 'm gonna draw 20 cc 's . You handle the injections .
When the EEG flatlines , the brain is dead .
I 'll be exploring .
Give me 30 seconds . Flip the blanket onto warm and take me up to 93 degrees , slowly .
Inject 1 cc of adrenalin , and at one minute , Joe , you come in with the defibs .
And you bring me back to life . With brain damage .
Resembling in many ways a Cabbage Patch doll .
Not with a body temperature of 86 degrees .
Dr. Mannus , will you handle the injections ?
Wait a minute . Wait . Quite simply , why are you doing this ?
Quite simply to see if there is anything out there beyond death .
Philosophy failed . Religion failed .
Now it 's up to the physical sciences . I think mankind deserves to know .
So you 're doing this for mankind ?
This letter absolves you of any responsibility . Just in case .
This isn 't for mankind . This is for Nelson .
Why do I suddenly see you on 60 Minutes ,
sandwiched in between Andy Rooney and a Subaru commercial .
" Tonight , a brilliant young medical student who dared to experience death and come back . "
Fame is inevitable . That 's the wrong reason .
It 's the right idea .
Dr. Hurley , electrodes . Come on , Joe , don 't you want to be on 60 Minutes ?
[ ♪ ♪ ]
Rachel , how about a little nitrous ? At least I get to go out with a laugh .
Dr. Hurley , get the blanket .
We 're all professionals . I 'm sure this 'll go very smoothly .
Nelson , if you die , can I have your apartment ?
It 's a joke . It 's a joke ! NELSON : One minute .
Don 't be late . Start filming now .
You 'll have a complete record of the experiment .
Promise me you 'll go through with this .
[ MONITOR BEEPING ]
One little kiss goodbye .
I 'll see you soon .
Ninety-six degrees .
STECKLE : This letter does not mean shit .
Oh , please . Let him sleep it off . He 'll have a wet dream and think he went to heaven , okay ?
Good idea . Good night , Nelson .
Now I know why I 'm here .
I 've expressed myself very clearly for the record , good night .
Steckle 's right . Are you willing to risk everything , med school , your future , for Nelson 's fame ?
Someone 's coming ! Oh , shit .
Is he dead ? STECKLE : He 's only sleeping .
Thank God you 're here to talk some sense into these people .
I 'll do it . What ?
You 're taking over ? I 've got nothing to lose .
Just his life ! I can get him back .
Just stop his heart . One minute , bring him right back .
Don 't think I couldn 't have .
No !
Clear . What the fuck are you doing ?
LABRACCIO : Asystole .
You 're killing him . It 's called murder .
No wonder you got tossed .
This is not the kind of shit I want on my transcript .
STECKLE : Please don 't . Don 't do anymore .
I did not come to medical school to murder my classmates , no matter how deranged they might be .
[ MONITOR BEEPING ]
Flatline .
STECKLE : They 're getting smaller . He 's dying .
Brain death . Now it 's real .
Start filming .
Let me defib him . He 's dead , isn 't that enough ? Let me try to bring him back .
Just watch the door .
Excuse me , I don 't want to ruin anyone 's evening , but are we in the room with a dead man ?
STECKLE : Oh , my God . One minute to go .
Start filming !
[ ♪ ♪ ]
Thirty seconds to go .
LABRACCIO : Okay , here we go , let 's heat him up .
Twenty seconds at 89 , 90 , 91 ...
Standing by with sodium bicarb and epi .
Charging the paddles .
LABRACCIO : Charged .
RACHEL : Monitor the EKG .
Body temp , 93 degrees . All right , here we go . Clear !
LABRACCIO : What have we got ? Not a goddamn thing .
Up me to 300 . Charged .
All clear .
STECKLE : Begin CPR .
Sodium bicarbonate and epi in . LABRACCIO : Bag him . Breathe .
Oh , my God . Oh , my God .
[ DOG BARKING ]
Look at it . Not a goddamn thing !
Ninety-eight degrees . Hit him again . 350 . Clear !
STECKLE : Nothing . Nothing .
Got him !
[ GASPING ]
RACHEL : STECKLE , help me . LABRACCIO : Epi . More epi .
STECKLE : In .
[ PANTING ]
REM . We got REM .
Nelson , can you hear us ? LABRACCIO : Welcome back , man .
Nelson , you crazy motherfucker , you did it !
Jesus Christ !
STECKLE , that 's some bedside manner . You 're gonna make one hell of a doctor .
Suck me .
[ ♪ ♪ ]
[ JOE WHOOPS ]
STECKLE : Can you recall any specific emotion or sensation ? Heat , cold , anything like that ?
You can 't break it down into specifics .
RACHEL : They say they see a tunnel of light at the end .
No . No , but there is something out there . It 's comforting .
Do you have any idea how big this is ? Can you even imagine ?
JOE : You walked on the moon , buddy .
Okay , okay , he could use some air . I think you guys could get him some fluids .
Thanks for saving my life . STECKLE : Lt was so much fun .
Let 's get that blood pressure going .
Are you all right , wise one ?
Dave , I feel like a highly tuned instrument .
Can you hear the traffic on the lake shore ?
Uh-huh .
Underneath that there 's a hum .
It 's the streetlights .
All right .
Even fainter I can hear a kind of dragging sound .
And it 's getting louder . No .
I not only hear it , I can feel it .
Yeah , well , your prognosis is excellent . You 'll look great on 60 Minutes .
It 's bigger than that , David .
By the time you 're through with it , I 'm sure it will be .
[ CHUCKLES ]
You 're not buying any of this . You forgot , I 'm an atheist .
Are you all right for a few minutes ? Yeah .
How 's he doing ? Well , physically he 's stable .
He 's talking like Lazarus back from the dead .
That 's what we did , right ? We brought him back from the dead .
All we did was get lucky .
I would like to go next . Forget it .
Me too . Seriously .
Why shouldn 't we all get famous from this ?
That 's not what this is about , Joe .
Yeah , Hurley , you 're gonna be famous . They 're gonna build monuments to you .
Little stone ones , about this high . " Rest in Peace . "
Like it or not , I 'm going next .
I 'd be willing to go one minute 20 seconds .
One thirty .
STECKLE : Are you two crazy ?
Or are you just so tragically competitive that you would enter into a bidding war with your lives ?
One thirty .
That 's it then . Not a bad price to pay for fame and glory .
Die to be a hero , but don 't die to be a celebrity .
[ ELECTRICITY BUZZING ]
[ METAL JINGLING ]
[ ♪ ♪ ]
[ DOG WHIMPERING ]
Champ ?
LABRACCIO : I think someone ought to stay with him tonight .
STECKLE : I have class in three hours .
RACHEL : I will .
LABRACCIO : All right . Are you okay ?
I 'd like to go home .
[ ♪ ♪ ]
[ DOG BARKING ]
[ KIDS SHOUTING ]
[ NELSON SCREAMING ]
[ NELSON PANTING ]
Are you okay ? You were hyperventilating .
Your can expect your blood pressure to rise .
Cardiovascular vessels will constrict , increasing your blood supply .
God , you 're beautiful . Get some rest .
Hey .
I bet 24 hours ago you didn 't think you 'd be spending the night here .
You were lucky last night , Nelson . Don 't push it .
So I want to wish you two the best of everything together .
[ PEOPLE LAUGHING ON TV ]
I know you 'll be healthy and wealthy and happy together in your wealth .
[ PEOPLE CHATTERING ON TV ]
JOE : Hello , may I please speak to Anne Coldren ?
ANNE [ OVER PHONE ] : Hello ? Anne ?
ANNE : Hi , I have been thinking about you all day . How are you ?
JOE : Counting the days to Thanksgiving break .
Me too . You know , I 've got to transfer to a school closer to you or get a faster car .
Sometimes I wonder , maybe we should 've gotten married last summer .
ANNE : My mother wasn 't ready yet .
You know , honey , you 're the best .
And if anything should ever happen ...
Joe , what 's wrong ? I don 't know . I 'm just tired .
I 'm not making any sense . Look , honey , I should go .
Joe , you 're scaring me . It 's okay , nothing 's wrong .
I love you . Bye .
[ SPEAKING INDISTINCTLY ]
[ PEOPLE CHEERING ON TV ]
[ ♪ ♪ ]
[ SPEAKS INDISTINCTLY ]
NURSE : It 's a boy .
[ SPEAKING INDISTINCTLY ]
[ MONITOR BEEPING ]
STECKLE : Nothing . NELSON : Starting CPR .
One , 1000 . Two , 1000 .
Three , 1000 . Four , 1000 .
CPR and adrenalin , and nothing !
One forty-five . What 's going on ? Come on , Joe !
Come on , Nelson , let me try . Five , 1000 .
Nothing . We 're running out of time !
Two , 1000 . Three , 1000 .
Come on , Nelson , let me try . I 'm doing everything I fucking can !
Breathe . Let him try .
Nelson , step back . Come on , Joe !
One , 1000 , two , 1000 , three , 1000 , four , 1000 , five . 1000 . Breathe !
[ LABRACCIO COUNTING ]
[ ♪ ♪ ]
[ WOMEN MOANING ]
[ COUGHING ]
STECKLE : I got him . O2 .
O2 up .
CPR successful . Hurley lives .
RACHEL : It 's okay , Joe .
It was great . Here it comes .
NELSON : Why don 't you just let him talk , Dave ?
RACHEL : Define " great . "
I don 't know , it 's not thinking about the past or the future .
It 's difficult to explain . Maybe impossible .
Yeah , dying is funny that way .
Dave , Nelson 's right , there definitely is activity beyond death .
Absolutely . JOE : The experience was strange .
It was almost erotic . He 's dead and he gets laid .
Wait a sec . What do you mean , erotic ?
I don 't want you to think it was casually , wantonly sexual by any means .
No , that never would have occurred to me in a million years , no way .
It was friendly . Lt was something vaguely feminine guiding me .
This could be the conquest of our generation . The last great frontier .
First you had the sea , then America , the West , the Moon ,
Mr. Leary , drugs , the inner journey ,
Ms. MacLaine , and our illustrious former First Lady , the outer journey .
But this , this is ours ! Well , we did have disco .
We have finally found something worthwhile , something to upstage those fucking baby boomers .
Watch your mouths .
I found something . Okay , let 's not forget that .
I came back from the dead tonight .
It doesn 't surprise me . We had Elvis in here last night .
Pay when you 're ready , okay ?
Joe , did you find it difficult at the end , getting back ?
No , not that I remember .
But you remember everything else ? I think you guys are full of shit .
I 'm not buying any of this . I probably wouldn 't buy it either ,
unless I 'd been there . So , what about it , Dave ?
Yeah , you 're an atheist . You got nothing to lose , right ?
I 'm going next .
Nobody 's going next . You 're looking for answers ? There 's no answers here .
I think you just saw what you wanted to see .
Give it up . It 's too dangerous . Who the hell are you to ... ?
We can 't turn back now . I 'm going further . One fifty .
Two minutes . Whoa , whoa , whoa , you just said ...
I changed my mind . Two minutes .
Two ten . Two twenty .
Well , looks like we found a winner .
LABRACCIO : Enjoying yourself , Nelson ?
Joe ...
was there anything negative about your experience ? Anything negative at all ?
No . Nothing .
Good . Good .
Hey . Hey ! Hold on . Was that your idea of chivalry ?
No , absolutely not .
Were you trying to show me up ? Not everything is about you .
Nobody seems to want me to go under . I don 't need your protection .
Well , there seems to be a lot of speculation about what you do need , Mannus .
Oh , does there ? And what did you decide in your infinite wisdom ?
I decided that when someone is as smart and driven as you are , and incredibly beautiful ,
it makes the rest of us very nervous .
Why did you change your mind ?
Because I 'm the skeptic , I 'm the control in this experiment . I should go next .
If there 's nothing out there , then I am not gonna convince myself that there is ,
and then there 's no reason for us to go any further .
Okay , but how do you explain the similarity in death experiences all over the world ?
People from different cultures and religions all seeing the same things in the same order .
I don 't know . Maybe there 's some chemical or a hormone released from the brain
at the time of death that makes it more palatable to us .
No , you 're reaching .
What if you go and there is something out there ?
Well , then you can kill yourself for as long as you want .
I 'm not going to kill myself .
I 'm glad to hear that , Mannus . I really haven 't known you for very long ,
but I get the feeling like I might miss you .
So why this obsession with death ? It 's not an obsession . It 's an interest .
It 's a personal interest .
Okay . Good night .
Can I drive you home ? No , thanks .
[ SIREN WAILING ]
[ WHIRRING ]
[ WOMAN SHOUTING INDISTINCTLY ]
[ ♪ ♪ ]
WOMAN : I didn 't take the money .
I got the toaster , but too many appliances make you lonely .
Right , Nelson ?
Because in the end , we all know what we 've done .
[ DOG WHIMPERING ]
Champ ?
Champ !
[ NELSON WHISTLES ]
Come on , boy . Come here , Champ .
Come here , boy . Come on , Champ .
What are you doing here , kid ? Are you all right ?
Hey . You okay ?
What are you doing here ? Are you lost ?
[ NELSON GRUNTING ]
[ NELSON COUGHING ]
STECKLE : Halloween morning . Rotting pumpkins , burning leaves ,
black cats mating like rats in the alley .
It was ... It were as if we felt no fear .
As if we were already dead , and had nothing to lose by dying .
Or perhaps it was because we lived life so well , and loved life so much ,
that we imagined ourselves immortal .
Overwhelming the powers that be with the force of our passion for science .
Or maybe we were just fucked in the head .
Hey , I 'm Joe Hurley . You 're Terry , right ?
TERRY : Uh-huh .
Listen , I heard you had a near-death experience .
TERRY : I don 't want to talk about it .
Hey . Wait a minute . I had a near-death experience also .
You did ? Yes , and I need someone to talk to .
Terry , this thing changed my life .
First of all , they didn 't even believe me .
What the hell do they know ? We were there , right ?
I want you to tell me all about it . But if you 've gotta go to class ,
maybe we can get together some night this week and discuss it ?
You know , all that day I knew something was going to happen .
[ CROWD CHEERING ON TV ]
I 've always had premonitions . Once , my aunt was supposed to fly in from Las Vegas ...
[ ♪ ♪ ]
[ TERRY SPEAKING INDISTINCTLY ]
Why did you do this to me , Joe ?
[ BRAKES SQUEALING ]
[ GRUNTS ]
[ ♪ ♪ ]
[ METAL JINGLING ]
[ SCRATCHING ]
Shit .
No !
Trick or treat .
[ DAVE STEWART 'S " PARTY TOWN " PLAYING ]
I don 't know , you guys . It 's Halloween . There 's a full moon .
Don 't you think we might be pushing it just a little bit ?
[ DOOR OPENS ]
Sorry I 'm late .
LABRACCIO : What the hell happened to your face ?
Some guys , some very big guys . Lt doesn 't matter .
RACHEL : Let me take a look at it . I 'm fine .
[ DOOR OPENS ]
STECKLE : Where the hell have you been ?
I don 't feel very well . What the hell happened to you ?
Enough . Worry about your camera .
Nice outfit .
Are you ready ? LABRACCIO : I 'm ready .
Who are you supposed to be ? Boner Man ?
Two twenty , don 't forget .
You just hurry up and get back .
You can buy us breakfast . LABRACCIO : Hey , Nelson .
Don 't let go of the rope .
Hoka hey .
RACHEL : See you soon .
[ ♪ ♪ ]
Twenty cc 's sodium pentothal in .
Eighty-six degrees .
RACHEL : Two hundred joules charged .
Clear .
[ BEEPING ]
STECKLE : Flatline .
What hangs in the air palpably ? Is it hope , is it fear ?
Is it the musky mist of death ?
Shut up , STECKLE . No , you shut up !
What if he didn 't make it back ?
Would you miss him , Rachel ?
One minute .
[ ♪ ♪ ]
[ GIRLS SINGING AND CLAPPING ]
RACHEL : Ninety degrees . Give him another five seconds .
What ? Ten . Why not 10 ?
We 've got a little time to decide .
Are you serious ?
Joey . I trusted you , Joe .
Stations . Joe , you 're blocking our view .
Come on , guys , no kidding around here .
Who 's kidding ?
What the hell 's going on here ? Ninety-two degrees .
Joe , get it !
Come on , 2 : 15 , 2 : 16 , 2 : 17 , 2 : 18 ...
Two-twenty . Hand it over .
[ CHUCKLES ]
This is my lab . Three hundred joules .
Charged .
Clear .
[ GIRLS SINGING AND CLAPPING ]
NELSON : Breathe ! Sodium bicarb and epi in .
One , 1000 , two , 1000 . What comes next ?
Knock it off , Nelson !
Five , 1000 . Breathe .
Three hundred joules charged . Clear .
Come on , Dave .
[ GIRLS SINGING AND CLAPPING ]
[ BEEPING ]
STECKLE : That 's it , that 's it !
RACHEL : That 's not it . He 's stuck in v-fib ! Charging again , 300 .
You 're hot . JOE : Try Lidocaine .
STECKLE : At 2 : 45 , atropine . RACHEL : Not yet , STECKLE . Clear .
Come on , Dave . Come on .
RACHEL : Increasing to 360 . Charge . Clear .
JOE : Go to Lidocaine . RACHEL : He won 't hold the beat .
Three fucking minutes .
Starting CPR . One , 1000 . Atropine in .
Joe , keep filming . I 'm gonna bring him back . Five , 1000 . Breathe .
You lied to me , Joe .
[ NELSON COUNTING ]
STECKLE : We lost him . RACHEL : Lidocaine push .
STECKLE : Somebody do something .
RACHEL : Three sixty , charged . Clear .
[ BEEPING ]
NELSON : Got him ! RACHEL : O2 standing by .
One mg epi in .
That sounds good . That was close , boy .
Oh , my God , that was close . That was way too close . Okay ? That was too close .
Hoka hey . What did you say there ?
Hoka hey . It 's the war cry of the Sioux Indians . Very macho . Lt means ...
" Today is a good day to die . " So was it , Dave ? Was today a good day to die ?
I don 't know if I was dead . I may have felt something .
Like a dream or just a bunch of stuff stored up inside my mind .
You were brain-dead . There was no mind .
Yeah , but some electrical current still circulating through my body ...
Lt would 've shown up on the EEG . You were dead . So why don 't you just tell us what happened ?
Well , it 's hard to verbalize .
It 's like being paranoid without the fear .
Like being watched . But that was probably just you guys were standing over me .
Who could be watching ? The dead .
I didn 't say that .
But the skeptic did feel something . I 'm going again .
No way , Nelson ! I 've been bumped twice .
Bidding starts at four minutes . RACHEL : Four minutes ?
Yeah . Labraccio went for 3 : 50 .
That was a mistake . We almost lost him .
Anything under four minutes would be redundant .
No one is going for four minutes !
Four twenty-five . Five minutes .
I 'm next or I 'm out for good .
LABRACCIO : Without her help , five minutes is gonna be hard enough .
But without me ... Or me .
JOE : Count me out too , Nelson .
Well , mutiny at last .
I trusted you , all of you , with an idea that was so simple and brilliant . You get one in a lifetime .
Give it a rest , Nelson . No , you give it a rest !
None of you had the foresight or the balls to do any of this until I did it .
Rachel , you want to go next ? Be my guest .
Fuck the rest of you . This was my idea .
You 're just tourists .
Hey , I would 've gone 3 : 30 or 3 : 40 . I still might .
But , Joe , 4 : 25 is crazy . We 're pushing the five-minute mark here . It 's dangerous .
[ STECKLE SPEAKING INDISTINCTLY ]
[ ♪ ♪ ]
You shit , Joe .
You said you loved me , Joe .
I love you , Joe . STECKLE : Yoo-hoo . Buddy ?
Skeletor , are you listening to me ?
[ ♪ ♪ ]
[ NELSON GRUNTING ]
[ NELSON SCREAMING ]
Thanks for staying .
I 'm on the early shift . You seem fine . I 'll see you later .
LABRACCIO : Wait , wait , wait .
About tonight ... Don 't try to talk me out of it .
Why are you doing this ?
Look , I 've lost people that are close to me .
I just want to make sure they 've gone to a good place . Does that seem trivial ?
To tell you the truth , it 's the best reason I 've heard yet for going .
But , listen , there 's something I didn 't tell you about last night .
I had this feeling that if I had gone any further ,
that there was something out there protecting me .
You know , something good .
So you don 't need to go under . The atheist now believes in God ?
I 'm trying to tell you that I don 't want you to do it .
Think about all we 'll have to talk about when you bring me back .
I 'm dying . Don 't lie to me .
Mrs. Amsler , you 've put up a great fight .
Sometimes we just have to let go . That 's what the voices say .
What voices ?
They say , " Have you done enough ? "
" Have you told everyone you love them ? "
I have . I have .
It 's okay .
They 're friendly voices . They 're telling you what you need to know .
What ? That you have someplace to go .
Do you believe that ? Yes , I do .
Yes , I do .
[ ♪ ♪ ]
GIRL : Hey ! Hey , fellatio !
Got a match ? Well , I do .
Your face and my ass .
Your breath and a buffalo fart .
Do I know you ?
You don 't know jack shit ! Butt-wad , needle-dick , cock-bite ,
jack-off , limp-wrist , corn-hole ,
banana-breath , shit-bird , bird-turd , turd-face ,
kiss-ass , brown-nose , macho-wimp , limp-dick , fart-face , turd-merchant !
What 's the matter ? Gonna cry ? Cry-baby Davie . Cry , cry , cry !
Shit-faced , rat-turd , ass-licking son of a bitch .
[ PANTING ]
[ THUNDER RUMBLING ]
How did it happen ? I was playing hockey .
Look , about last night ... It 's okay .
No-show Labraccio . This really isn 't like him .
It 's his way of trying to stop me . It won 't work , I 'm ready .
It 's not a good idea to do this without David .
We don 't need Dave . Can you do this ?
Can you trust me ? No , but let 's do it anyway .
Nitrous on .
See you soon .
[ ♪ ♪ ]
How long 's she been under ? One-twenty .
We 're bringing her back . No , we 're not .
Get that blanket to warm . Body temp ?
She hasn 't been under long enough . Just do it , Joe .
Joe , we said 4 : 25 Just do it !
Don 't expect any hugs and kisses for this .
[ ♪ ♪ ]
Waiting for body temp to rise . Aborting fourth experiment . Why , Dave ?
Why don 't you ask Dr. Death ? STECKLE : Ninety degrees .
What 's going on , Nelson ? Nothing .
Just bringing Rachel back early , that 's all .
That 's all , huh ? Don 't start now . Think about Rachel .
Joe 's right . Ninety-one degrees . Let 's be ready .
[ ELECTRICITY CRACKLING ]
[ ♪ ♪ ]
[ MAN SPEAKING INDISTINCTLY ]
Rachel , don 't go in there .
I told you not to do that .
Denny !
It 's your fault !
[ GUNSHOT ]
[ MONITOR BEEPING ]
Nothing . NELSON : Take me up to 300 .
LABRACCIO : Three hundred ? You 're hot .
JOE : Come on , Rachel . STECKLE : No , not a thing . 2 : 05 .
LABRACCIO : You 're hot . NELSON : Clear .
JOE : Come on , Rachel . Come on ! LABRACCIO : Shit !
Oh , no ! Denny !
NELSON : Three hundred joules . Clear !
Got her ! STECKLE : V-fib .
We don 't have her .
It 's okay , we 'll get her . Step me up to 360 . Clear .
What the hell is going on ? What did you do to me ? I had her .
Fuse . A short , maybe a circuit .
Joe , you charged the battery ? Shit !
Oh , shit . Starting CPR . Bag her , STECKLE .
[ COUNTING ]
LABRACCIO : No pulse . JOE : Epi in .
[ NELSON COUNTING ]
[ SCREAMING ]
It 's not working . Joe , take over . Got her .
Four minutes . She 's been under four minutes .
[ JOE COUNTING ]
We 're moving to bretylium . LABRACCIO : No .
It 's the only way . No !
It 's our last chance .
Don 't do it , you 'll fry her .
LABRACCIO : Nelson !
Please , don 't !
You 'll bring her back ?
[ JOE COUNTING ]
LABRACCIO : Come on , Mannus . You can do it .
Lidocaine in .
Come on back to us . Come on .
Wait ! Shh , shh , shh ! I got something .
I hear something .
O2 ! O2 !
She 's back .
I still don 't understand why you stopped us .
Something happened to me today . Something very strange .
That 's why you stopped us ?
There was this girl . Winnie Hicks , I think it was .
I was in elementary school with her .
We used to make fun of her .
I was on the train , and I heard someone calling me names .
I turned around , I swear to God , she was standing right in front of me !
Still only 10 years old . Maybe it was a hallucination .
Maybe you fell asleep . Thoughts triggered by submerged guilt .
LABRACCIO : No , I was not asleep .
Guys , I 've seen some odd things from my past too .
I thought it was brain damage . In your case it probably is .
I 'm gonna get some of this on tape .
JOE : STECKLE , shut that off , this is personal .
LABRACCIO : Go ahead , Joe .
I 've been haunted by images of women that I videotaped without them knowing .
They 're all members of the Joe Hurley Video Library .
What ?
What about you , Nelson ? Who 's come looking for you ?
His name 's Billy Mahoney . He 's a kid we picked on in school .
It 's no big deal . No big deal , huh ?
Then what happened to your face ?
Sometimes the little fella gets carried away .
Wait a minute . Wait .
I can understand Dave nodding off on the train , and pervert here having a couple of flashbacks .
You 're saying this guy physically touches you ?
That is not a hallucination and it is not possible !
This whole lab 's not possible ! Or is it ?
This is too weird . Weird ? We 've experienced death .
Now somehow we 've brought our sins back physically . And they 're pissed .
When did you know about this ? I had my suspicions after Joe went .
Before I went . Before she went . And you didn 't say a word !
That 's wrong , Nelson . Jesus Christ ! We 're scientists .
Call yourself a scientist ? It 's reckless , immoral and unethical for you to withhold your findings .
Rachel Mannus may have the answers to life and death .
She was under for five minutes !
Now , if she walks out of that ladies ' room with those answers ...
the whole world will worship her .
Just like you do . You should 've told us , Nelson .
You wouldn 't have done it . At least we would 've had a choice !
We 're fucked .
Rachel , are you all right ? I 'm okay . I 'm okay .
[ WATER RUNNING ]
[ DOOR CLOSES ]
I said I was fine .
[ FOOTSTEPS ]
Are you guys gonna watch me ?
[ ♪ ♪ ]
[ METAL CREAKING ]
[ CHUCKLES ]
Come on , Billy Mahoney . Come on .
Give it your best shot .
I dare you . I fucking dare you .
Things from our past , they want revenge ?
I don 't know . I 'm not exactly sure how it works .
But if you see anything , I want you to talk to me about it . All right ? Whatever it is .
You just tell the doctor .
I 'll be in the living room if you need anything .
Is it people who we 've hurt or wronged in some way ?
Did something happen tonight ? Ls there something you want to talk to me about ?
No .
Just try to get some rest .
How 's she doing ? I think she 's hiding something .
Like what ? Ls there any heebie-jeebie stuff going on ?
What do you think Nelson did to that kid ?
How the hell am I supposed to know ?
STECKLE : It 's really important that we keep each other informed .
Yeah , I 'm sorry .
Why don 't you guys take off ? I 'll stay with her .
Are you okay ? Yeah , I 'm fine . I 'm sorry .
I 'm sorry . I 'm sorry .
[ ♪ ♪ ]
[ KIDS SHOUTING ]
We 're gonna get you , Billy Mahoney !
[ BARKING ]
No ! Sorry ! No ! No ! No !
No , stop ! Stop , Nelson !
[ YELLS ]
No !
[ FOOTSTEPS RUNNING ]
[ ♪ ♪ ]
[ DOOR OPENS ]
How are you doing ? I 'm late . I 'll see you later .
Wait . Where are you going ?
I 'm late . I have to talk to her . I 've gotta stop her .
Talk to who ?
EDNA : Good morning , Rachel .
RACHEL : No , no . No , no .
I wanted to tell her the voices were wrong . There 's nothing beautiful out there .
Rachel , you gotta get used to losing them . It 's part of our work .
But I was wrong .
[ GIRLS CLAPPING AND SINGING ]
[ KIDS SPEAKING INDISTINCTLY ]
[ ♪ ♪ ]
You look like you 're enjoying the day .
Yeah , right .
Don 't you remember me , Joe ? Yes , of course .
Are you a model ? You could be . Look , I 've got to go .
I 'm not picking you up . I just picked you out .
Mind if I buy you a drink ? No , thanks .
I 'll call you this weekend . I 've been looking for a study partner .
Fine , I 'm in the book .
Hey , gorgeous . Who are you ?
What are you doing ?
Some crazy girl ... I know you , don 't I ?
Would you like to ? We don 't have to do anything .
We can just lie together . Hold each other in our underwear .
I 'll call you . I promise .
I 'm tired of playing the field .
We can stop whenever you want .
It 'll only make our relationship better .
I 've never felt like this before .
WOMAN 1 : I 'm tired of playing the field .
WOMAN 2 : Of course I respect you .
WOMAN 3 : We can stop whenever you want .
Joe .
Joey .
Mmm , Joseph .
Carl . WOMAN 3 : ... whenever you want .
I need you to show me that you love me .
You 're not real !
Anne , is that you ?
Is it really you ? You sounded so upset on the phone .
I was worried . I took the bus down . What a great surprise .
How long have you been here ? Long enough to see your tapes .
JOE : Oh , my God !
You know , the worst part is , you 're gonna think I 'm leaving you because you slept with those girls .
They meant nothing to me .
I wish they had meant something . If you were honest , if you had cared for any of them ,
then I could have fought that . I loved you .
But to film all those girls without them knowing it , to have so little respect ...
Those women trusted you . What kind of marriage can we have
when you have no understanding of trust .
Anne , please .
It 's not what you think . Yes , it is .
LABRACCIO : Hello , is this Mrs. Earl R. Hicks ?
This is a strange question . Do you have a daughter Winnie , about 26 years old ?
You do ? I 'm David Labraccio . I was in school with Winnie .
Yeah , my parents still live there .
I wanted to get in touch with her and I was wondering ...
Right .
Okay . And do you have an address for her ?
Great . I really appreciate it . Bye-bye .
Jesus ! It looks as bad as it feels , huh ?
You want me to take a look at it ? No . How 's Rachel doing ?
She didn 't come out of that bathroom with the answers to life and death .
I gotta go .
Where are you going ? Bensenville .
Can I go ?
It 's a two-hour drive .
Look , I don 't want to be alone .
Today , we are going to remove the left kidney and dissect the lower intestines .
I would like you to remove the ascending colon from the transverse colon .
Proceed to the sigmoid colon and on to the appendix .
Remove the appendix , taking note of the blood supply .
Where the hell are you going ? Are you okay ?
I would be fine if everyone would stop asking me if I 'm all right .
Are you crazy ? JOE : Yes !
Is she getting the heebie-jeebies ? I 'm the one who 's spooking .
Getting us kicked out of med school won 't get Anne back . Now you get to work .
[ ♪ ♪ ]
[ WHIMPERS ]
[ RACHEL SCREAMS ]
PROFESSOR : Mannus ! Mannus !
I 'll handle this . Back to work or suffer the consequences .
Fuck it .
LABRACCIO : This must be it . NELSON : Winnie did well for herself .
She 's probably not even gonna remember who you are .
It 's worth a shot .
Are you coming ? No .
Listen , if anything happens ... If you need me , just honk the horn .
Okay .
[ ♪ ♪ ]
[ DOORBELL RINGS ]
Ring , ring , ring . Dave , you should 've sent a letter .
Hello ? Anybody home ?
[ DOOR OPENS ]
Hi , is your mother at home ? WOMAN : Coming .
Go in the house , baby .
Yes ? Can I help you ? Yeah , I think you can .
You 're Winnie Hicks , aren 't you ? From Claremont ?
Yes .
Yeah , I 'm David Labraccio . We went to S. B. Butler together .
Really ?
I was a little smaller then .
I just drove up from the city . That 's my truck there .
Hi .
Hello , I 'm nice . He 's nice .
We 're both fucking lunatics . Can I come in , please ?
LABRACCIO : Thanks a lot .
I 've got to hand it to you , Dave , you 've got guts .
[ ♪ ♪ ]
Wow , this is great . It 's beautiful .
Looks like you 've done well for yourself .
Well , it isn 't medical school .
But I never liked school anyway .
I wasn 't very good at it .
I 'm surprised you even remember me .
Oh , yeah , I do remember you .
I also remember the way we treated you back then .
You were a little shy , and I was a real jerk and I 'm sorry .
I mean , I just ... I wanted to say I 'm sorry .
What are you talking about ?
That was so long ago I don 't even remember what you could have done .
Let 's not dredge up all that stuff . Sherry , go on in the house .
However we made you feel , it was wrong .
I mean , we were wrong .
Go on .
I have a family now .
I haven 't been that ugly little girl in quite some time .
You were never ugly .
Why did you come here ?
[ ♪ ♪ ]
David , help !
It was just kids . I know how kids are . Lt didn 't mean anything .
Listen , I didn 't mean to come here ...
Winnie , are you all right ?
I 'm fine , Ben . Everything 's okay .
Okay .
I 'm sorry if I made you feel bad . I didn 't want to hurt you again .
I 'm gonna go .
David ?
Thank you .
Are you sure ?
Thanks .
[ ♪ ♪ ]
[ PANTING ]
Oh , shit !
David ! David , help ! David !
Shit .
No !
[ GRUNTING ]
[ LAUGHING ]
No !
[ GRUNTING ]
[ SCREAMS ]
Nelson !
Jesus .
Nelson , stop . Stop , man ! Nelson , stop !
Stop ! Stop it !
Where 's Billy Mahoney ? Where is he ?
There is no Billy . There 's no one here , man . It 's just the two of us . We 're all alone .
Let go !
Where the hell have you guys been ?
She freaked in class . We 've been with her all day .
How are you doing ?
I 'm fine . Fine , for somebody who keeps running into her father
who 's been dead for 20 years .
" Death is beautiful . " What a bunch of crap .
[ TRUCK DOOR OPENS ]
How you doing , Nelson ? You okay ?
I 'd like to thank you for the nightmare .
Hey , you guys were all so eager to jump on my coattails . Well , welcome aboard .
You withheld information . That 's the same as lying .
Oh . I 'm sorry you 're so upset .
You think you 're the only one that risked or lost a goddamn thing here ?
I always felt there was something profoundly unnatural about this .
JOE : Shut up , STECKLE . Talk about somebody who hasn 't risked a goddamn thing .
STECKLE : Screw yourself .
This is not gonna help ! Kiss my ass .
We 're all in this together . No , we 're not .
Wait a minute . Isn 't she strong ?
So independent .
When I get into trouble , I don 't drag everybody down with me .
Drag every ... ? Come on ! What happened to you ? You got caught with your videotapes down ?
You swore at a little girl on a playground . Aww !
And now you 're having bad dreams about your daddy .
I 'm really sorry ! You don 't know anything about me .
You never have .
But Dave does , doesn 't he ?
Come on , they 're your sins . Live with them . I do .
You want to see death ? Take a good look . Lt is beautiful .
You 've already hurt yourself . Do you want to hurt her too ? Ls that what you want ? Huh , do you ?
Help him find Billy Mahoney . JOE : How 's that gonna help ?
Goddamn it , Joe . Just help him find Billy , all right ?
Don 't leave him alone .
Why do we want to find Billy Mahoney ?
Because young Dr. Dave thinks he 's solved our karmic problems .
Atonement , gentlemen . Atonement ?
Wait a goddamn minute ! Jesus , you 're always running away from me .
Why don 't you talk to me ?
My father shot himself when I was 5 .
And you feel responsible ?
There was this door in our hallway and I wasn 't supposed to go in ...
Kids always feel responsible . You could not have been to blame .
David , you said it yourself . People we 've wronged want revenge .
I don 't know if this is gonna help , but going to see Winnie Hicks today ,
I mean , I don 't know how to explain it , but it lifted ...
[ ♪ ♪ ]
Somehow , just asking for forgiveness ...
Winnie Hicks is alive . My father 's dead .
Rachel , your father is in a good place .
He wants you to let him go .
Then why is he back ?
Here .
Where the hell are we ? We 'd better get you to a hospital .
Nelson .
[ ♪ ♪ ]
[ NELSON CHUCKLES ]
Come on , this is a shortcut . I can 't believe I remember all this .
Holy shit , the neighborhood 's falling apart .
Nelson ! Give me the keys ! STECKLE : Nelson !
" ' Step on a crack break your mother 's back ... "
[ DOGS BARKING ]
Olly Olly oxen free ! Last one over is a rotten egg !
Come on , boys , salvation just ahead .
This is a graveyard .
JOE : Nelson , where the fuck are you ? This isn 't funny anymore .
It never was .
Where the hell are you ? NELSON : Right here .
This is where Billy lives . Wake up , you little shit , you 've got company !
Wanna know how I knew he was here ?
Because I put him here .
Billy Mahoney ! No , Nelson , no , don 't do it !
[ BARKING ]
[ KIDS SHOUTING AND LAUGHING ]
No ! No !
[ LAUGHING ]
Please don 't ! No !
Ow !
[ SCREAMING ]
[ DOG WHIMPERS ]
I was taken away from my family when I was 9 years old .
I was sent to Stoneham School for Boys . I thought I 'd paid my dues !
It was an accident . Let 's go home , okay ?
Dave 's right . I can still make amends .
JOE : How ?
[ ♪ ♪ ]
Nelson ?
Joe , I gotta borrow your car . Nelson .
Nelson , wait .
[ CAR ENGINE STARTS ]
Oh , my God .
[ CREAKS ]
[ ♪ ♪ ]
[ PHONE RINGING ]
LABRACCIO : Hello . What ? Where ?
LABRACCIO : Rachel .
Nelson freaked out . Joe and STECKLE are stranded .
Will you be all right alone ? Yeah .
Are you sure ? Yeah .
[ ENGINE STARTS ]
Daddy .
Rachel .
Sweetheart .
I 'm sorry .
Do you forgive me ? Can you ever forgive me ?
[ SPEAKS INDISTINCTLY ]
[ ♪ ♪ ]
Billy Mahoney died 17 years ago , and whether he actually is or not , Nelson feels responsible .
Jesus Christ . Do you have any idea where he went ?
He ran off mumbling something about making amends .
How can you make amends with somebody who 's already dead ?
Oh , my God . You don 't think he 'd try to flatline without us , do you ?
That would be suicide .
[ ♪ ♪ ]
[ PHONE RINGING ]
David ? No , it 's Nelson .
Nelson , where are you ? David 's out trying to find you .
Rachel , I wanted to say I was sorry .
Please , tell David .
I 'm sorry for ever getting any of you involved in this .
No , you don 't understand . None of that matters now .
[ LAUGHS ]
Rachel , everything matters . Everything we do matters .
That 's why I 'm going under again . No , Nelson , wait .
Goodbye , Rachel . Tell me where you are .
I really am sorry . Nelson , please . Please ...
It 's payback for our arrogance . Save it , Randy .
[ ♪ ♪ ]
It 's a good thing I didn 't flatline .
My 350-pound babysitter would be running after me ,
waving the half-eaten pastrami sandwich I stole from her .
[ TIRES SCREECHING ]
Okay , Billy Mahoney , come on .
[ GRUNTING ]
Shit .
[ HISSING ]
[ BEEPING ]
[ KIDS SHOUTING AND LAUGHING ]
[ LAUGHING ]
[ ♪ ♪ ]
JOE : Oh , God . LABRACCIO : Body temp down to 78 .
Potassium ! He used potassium ! Oh , Christ .
[ KIDS SHOUTING ]
LABRACCIO : Joe , electrodes ! STECKLE : Calcium in .
Three hundred , clear .
[ SHOUTING ]
Nothing . We have to go again .
LABRACCIO : Clear . Nothing .
Stop !
[ LAUGHING ]
Up to 360 . Clear !
Nothing . I can 't hear anything . He called me . He called me .
It 's been over nine minutes . Nine minutes ?
All right , let 's intubate .
[ LABRACCIO COUNTING ]
Damn it , I can 't get it in . His trachea 's too tight .
Try again .
[ LABRACCIO COUNTING ]
LABRACCIO : Come on , Nelson !
Stop , Billy ! Stop , Billy !
No !
[ KIDS SHOUTING ]
[ DOG BARKING ] [ LAUGHING ]
STECKLE : Epi in !
[ COUNTING ]
STECKLE : Nothing . JOE : Eighty-eight degrees .
Get me 4 mg of atropine ready . STECKLE : Four ?
[ COUNTING ]
David ... Atropine intratracheal . Come on .
This is a truckload , Dave .
This has gotta work . This has gotta work . Come on back , Nelson .
Come on , come on , come on . Come on , Nelson .
Come on , Nelson .
LABRACCIO : Come on , Nelson . He 's been dead 10 minutes .
Bretylium . No , he 's not in v-fib .
STECKLE : He 's dead ! Epi intracardial .
STECKLE : No , Rachel , no .
Just do it !
YOUNG NELSON : No !
[ LAUGHING ]
Stop ! No ! Yeah .
Don 't do it , Billy ! Don 't !
I 'm sorry ! No ! No !
Oh !
[ SCREAMING ]
LABRACCIO : Starting CPR !
[ LABRACCIO COUNTING ]
It 's been 12 minutes ! He is dead .
Five , 1000 . Breathe !
[ COUNTING ]
Forget about it , Dave . We lost him .
No , you son of a bitch !
Stop it ! David , stop it !
Stop , David . Stop it , David . LABRACCIO : No !
Stop it , David !
David , stop it ! David ! David !
Let him go .
We 're all responsible for this . Maybe we deserve this .
No , no . It 's not fair and it 's not right .
I 'm sorry , God ! I 'm sorry we stepped on your fucking territory !
I 'm sorry ! Isn 't that enough ?
Apparently not . I 'll call the police .
I could hear it in his voice on the phone .
Nelson felt he deserved to die .
Bullshit ! Lt was a mistake . He was just a little kid .
And he doesn 't deserve to die !
[ ALL SHOUTING ]
[ ♪ ♪ ]
[ DEFIBRILLATOR ZAPS ]
[ JOE AND RACHEL SHOUTING ]
STECKLE : Come on , Nelson ! Come on !
LABRACCIO : Clear ! No , no , no , wait !
Oh , my God .
I got a pulse . I got a pulse . We 've got him ! We fucking got him !
Come on , Nelson , pick up the beat .
RACHEL : Easy , easy , easy . Don 't rush him . Oh , my God .
Come on , Nelson , pick up the beat . Pick up the beat , pick up the beat .
Don 't rush him .
[ ♪ ♪ ]
That 's it , that 's it , that 's it .
[ SWALLOWS ]
RACHEL : There we go .
Hail Mary , praise Jesus , and all that stuff . Oh , thank you , Jesus .
Hi , Nelson .
Don 't try to talk . I 've got to get this on tape .
[ NELSON WHISPERING ]
He said ...
He said it wasn 't such a good day to die .
Thank you .
[ ♪ ♪ ]